Guide to the Hervey Allen Papers, 1831-1965 SC.1952.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Projects, 1932-1949; VII.
  - St. John's College, 1938-1949; 2.
    - Friends of St. John's, 1948-1949 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, Undated, 1939-1949 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - The Great Teachers Return Seminar, 1948 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Naval Academy Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Publicity, Undated, 1940-1949 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Tangential Engine, 1942-1950; 3.
    Related material can be found in Box 120, Series XII: Projects, Subseries 2: St. John's College.
    In 1942-1943, Allen invented a rotary internal combustion motor called the Tangential Engine. Included in this subseries are blueprints, correspondence, patent information, and sketches relating to Allen's engine.
    - Blueprints, 1942 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1950 (Box 123, Folder 2-5)
    - Patent Information (Work of Other People), 1934 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Sketches (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - US War Manpower Commission, 1943-1945; 4.
    During World War II, Hervey Allen served as Regional Information Representative for the US War Manpower Commission. Due to domestic labor shortage during the war, President Roosevelt signed an executive order to establish the Commission whose primary charge was to draft policies that effectively managed and recruited labor for war and essential civilian industries. Allen was employed by the Commission for eight months but was forced to resign and become a non-paid consultant due to tax reasons. Several of Allen's close friends were also affiliated with the Commission including Philip S. Broughton and Frank Constangy. B.F. Ashe, President of the University of Miami, was the Regional Director of the Atlanta division of the Commission.
    Included in this subseries are correspondence and associated documents about the Commission.
    B.F. Ashe, Box 117, Folder 8. Philip Broughton, Box 48, Folder 7-8.
    - Correspondence with Frank Constangy, 1944-1948 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 124, Folder 2-4)
  - Other Academic Institutions, 1947-1949; 5.
    This subseries contains correspondence and material related to other academic institutions Hervey Allen was affiliated with as a member of the Board of Trustees.
    - Cazenovia Junior College for Women
      - Invitations, Pamphlets, and Articles, 1947-1949 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      - Board of Trustees, 1947-October 1948 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - Board of Trustees, December 1948-April 1949 (Box 124, Folder 7)
      - Board of Trustees, May-November 1949 (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - Ransom School (Adirondack-Florida School), 1949 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Washington and Jefferson College, 1948-1949 (Box 124, Folder 10)
- Estates and Financial Matters, 1919-1952; VIII.
  This series includes material that pertain to Hervey Allen's estate and financial matters. It includes correspondence and ephemera of the purchase and quotidian upkeep of his estates: Bonfield Manor, Felicity Hall, and The Glades, as well as correspondence that took place in Cazenovia, New York where the Allens lived with Ann Allen's parents' home for some time and where they purchased a summer home. Also included are bills and receipts, cancelled checks, insurance and tax documents.
  - Financial Matters, 1919-1950; 1.
    Material in this subseries is arranged on a folder-level according to year.
    - Bank of Manhattan, 1941-1942 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Coconut Grove Exchange Bank, 1941 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Farmers Merchant Bank, 1939-1941 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - General Ledger, 1933-1934 (Box 125, Folder 4-5)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1919-1933 (Box 126, Folder 1-4)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1934 (Box 127, Folder 1-5)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1935 (Box 128, Folder 1-8)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1935 (Box 129, Folder 1-7)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1936 (Box 130, Folder 1-4)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1936 (Box 131, Folder 1-8)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1937 (Box 132, Folder 1-5)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1938-1939 (Box 133, Folder 1-5)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1939-1940 (Box 134, Folder 1-7)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1940-1941 (Box 135, Folder 1-7)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1942-1943 (Box 136, Folder 1-4)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1944-1946 (Box 137, Folder 1-6)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1946-1949 (Box 138, Folder 1-7)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1949-1950 (Box 139, Folder 1-3)
    - Business Letters, 1933-1935 (Box 139, Folder 4-6)
    - Checks, 1922-1929 (Box 140, Folder 1-3)
    - Checks, 1930-1947 (Box 141, Folder 1-5)
    - Insurance Correspondence, 1933-1940 (Box 142, Folder 1-10)
    - Insurance Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 143, Folder 1-7)
    - Insurance Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
    - Insurance Policies and Forms, 1934-1941 (Box 144, Folder 3-5)
    - Ledgers and Notebooks, 1919-1934 (Box 144, Folder 6-7)
    - Royalties, 1924-1939 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Social Security, 1944 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Tax Forms, 1938-1948 (Box 145, Folder 3-13)
    - Miscellaneous Items Regarding Wills and Estate Matters Related to Hervey Allen, 1926-1939 (Box 145, Folder 14)
  - Homes, 1926-1950; 2.
    Includes correspondence between Allen and estate staff on matters of upkeep. Also included is information on the Bonfield fire.
    - Account Book, Bookkeeping, Guestbook, and Land Description, 1926-1936 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Account Book, Bookkeeping, Guestbook, and Land Description, 1926-1936 (Box 146, Folder 2-4)
    - Bonfield Manor, 1926-1934 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Bonfield Manor, 1926-1934 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Bonfield Manor, 1926-1934 (Box 147, Folder 3-11)
    - Bonfield Manor, 1934-1936 (Box 148, Folder 1-12)
    - Bonfield Manor, 1937-1949 (Box 149, Folder 1-7)
    - Cazenovia, 1933-1935 (Box 149, Folder 8-9)
    - Cazenovia, 1936-1949 (Box 150, Folder 1-2)
    - Felicity Hall, 1927-1936 (Box 150, Folder 3-5)
    - The Glades, 1926-1934 (Box 150, Folder 6-14)
    - The Glades, 1934-1935 (Box 151, Folder 1-9)
    - The Glades, 1935-1938 (Box 152, Folder 1-8)
    - The Glades, 1938-1940 (Box 153, Folder 1-10)
    - The Glades, 1940-1941 (Box 154, Folder 1-5)
    - The Glades, 1942-1950 (Box 155, Folder 1-11)
    - Posthumous Estate Matters, 1949-1952 (Box 155, Folder 12-15)
- Family Papers, 1831-1965; IX.
  The Family Papers series includes papers, correspondence, financial documents, genealogical information, photographs, scrapbooks, journals, and ephemeral material associated with the Allens, the Gills, and the Myers (maternal families).
  The Allen family lineage can be traced back to the immigrating generation of Edward Allen (1794-1874) and Millicent (Amelia) Bindley Allen (1797-1890) who immigrated from England. The series features a variety of personal family mementos from multi-generational members of the Allen family. Among the highlights of the series are scrapbooks and journals of Hervey Allen's great uncle, William Hervey Allen, a steamboat captain who survived a horrific accident on board the New Hampshire during which Allen's younger brother, George T. Allen, was killed. The series also features a separate subseries for the personal papers of Hervey Allen's grandfather, Colonel Edward Jay Allen.
  Hervey Allen's own photographs, scrapbooks, journals, and ephemera are included in this series. Since the majority of all photographs feature family members, all photographs are featured in this series.
  Oversized materials are located in Box 193. Family obituaries and other newspaper articles (collected or written by family members) can be found in Box 194.
  - Edward Jay Allen, 1848-1918; 1.
    Edward Jay Allen, Hervey Allen's paternal grandfather, was a Civil War colonel whose travels on the Oregon Trail made him a well-known and highly honored early pioneer of the Pacific Northwest territory. In 1852 at the age 22, he traveled west to Puget Sound via the Oregon Trail, documenting his experiences via correspondence and later recounting them in his manuscript, "Letters from the Oregon Trail." He settled in Olympia and remained in the Pacific Northwest for three years, surveying the land and acquainting himself with the native culture and language, the Chinook Jargon. In 1852, he became one of the signers of the Monticello Memorial, a resolution to Congress in favor of splitting the Oregon and Washington Territories.
    He returned east in 1855, and continued a successful career as an civil engineer, building roads, bridges, and railroads. He married Elizabeth Wilson Robinson on July 16th, 1857 in Pittsburgh. They had five children: William Hervey (Hervey Allen's father), Edna A. Rickmers, May L., Edward H., and Harold Allen.
    At the onset of the Civil War, Allen was working as a railroad contractor for the Virginia Central Railroad. During Virginia's secession from the Union, Allen narrowly escaped Confederate capture as he attempted to smuggle back to Pittsburgh. He volunteered on the Union side for some time in Washington DC and Virginia, repairing roads and bridges destroyed by the Confederates before returning to Pittsburgh and recruiting the 155th Regiment Pennsylvania Infantry in 1862. For three years, he headed the Infantry at the rank of Colonel. The Infantry fought at various battles including the Battle of Antietam and Fredericksburg.
    After the war, Colonel Allen dedicated himself to local work in Pittsburgh. He worked for the Pacific and Atlantic Telegraph Co. as a secretary and also became active in real estate. Allen became a larger than life figure, often writing about his life stories in local papers. He became an early supporter and patron of John W. Alexander, adopting the orphaned Alexander while he worked at the Pacific and Atlantic Telegraph Co. as a young man. Allen brought Alexander to the Allen home at "Edgehill" and painted various members of the Allen family, including Colonel Allen (see [Edward Jay Allen, Three-Quarter-Length Portrait, Standing, Face Right]). Colonel Allen died at the age of 85, on December 28, 1915; Mrs. Allen, his widow, died just five days after him.
    Featured in this subseries are Allen's typescript manuscript (re-told, original lost) of "The Oregon Trail," personal correspondence, Civil War memorabilia, journals, obituaries, notebooks, photographs, will and last testament, and other creative works, including his poem, "The Veteran."
    Oversized Material, Family, Box 193; Newspapers, Box 194. Oversized Material, Artwork Collection, Artwork on Display, [Edward Jay Allen, Three-Quarter-Length Portrait, Standing, Face Right].
    - Oregon Trail
      - Description on the Construction of a Military Road from Fort Walla Walla to Fort Steilacoom, by George H. Himes, [1844-1859] (Box 156, Folder 3)
        In early 1852, the introduction of a bill to construct a military road from Fort Walla Walla to Fort Steilacoom reached Congress by way of Joseph Lane, delegate to Congress from the Oregon Territory. The bill was met with opposition from Congress due to the lack of a topographical survey and approximate estimate cost. By December of that year, House Bill No. 187 passed, allotting $20,000 to the construction of this road. George H. Himes (1844-1940), historian at the Oregon Historical Society, wrote this document as he traced the construction of this road through newspaper articles of the The Columbian. He writes that on May 28, 1853 Edward Jay Allen joined a committee to "view out a route and report therson as follows"; Allen headed east to begin construction on the side of Steilacoom (page 2). The road was hoped to be constructed by the end of 1853 "to accommodate incoming immigrants" (page 2). This document also details some of the first settlements made from crossing the Columbia river to Puget Sound pre-1853.
      - Original Journal from the Oregon Trail, 1852; Frail. Please be careful. (Box 159, Folder 1)
        This is Edward Jay Allen's journal as he traversed the Oregon Trail. The journal is not written in chronological order. A flag has been set at the beginning of the journal, in the middle of the journal, on the June 2nd entry. The journal continues through and back the beginning of the book, and finally back to the adjacent page of the June 2nd entry, dated at October 4th. Writing includes calculations, lists of itemized expenses, and individuals' names on wagon trains.
      - Letters From the Oregon Trail: Carbon Copy, Part I (2 copies), [1852-1855]; 1908; 1913 (Box 156, Folder 1)
        Edward Jay Allen kept in extensive correspondence with his loved ones in Pittsburgh while on the Oregon Trail. After his return from the Northwest Territories, his letters were amalgamated into a narrative entitled, "Letters from the Oregon Trail." In this narrative, Allen details his quotidian adventures on the trail, starting at Council Bluffs (then Kanesville, Iowa): "[w]e knew but little of the country we should traverse, it was terra incognita. All the region that lay to the westward was marked on the map as the "Great American Desert" (page 3). Throughout his accounts, Allen encounters other pioneers venturing West, Native Americans, and details the strenuous labor and setbacks that he endured during his trip.
        The narrative is re-told and typewritten in 1913, with a preface from the author. External sources argue that the typewritten manuscript was actually written around 1908 (Larsen and Johnson).
        Folder 1 contains pages 1-112 and folder 2 contains pages 200-358.
        Please note: pages 113-199 are missing.
      - Letters From the Oregon Trail: Carbon Copy, Part 2, [1852-1855]; 1908; 1913 (Box 156, Folder 2)
      - Chinook Jargon: Carbon Copy and Photocopy, [1852-1855] (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - Civil War
      - Civil War Prose on Slavery (Box 156, Folder 5)
      - Certificate Of Permission For Entry into Virginia, 1862 (Box 157, Folder 1)
      - Membership Card For The Military Order Loyal Legion United States (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Program For The Dedication Of Monument In Memorial Of The 155th Regiment Of Pennsylvania, 1886 (Box 157, Folder 3)
      - Letter Of Recommendation For Rank Of Colonel, 1863 (Box 157, Folder 4)
      - Badges Of Reunions Held For The 155th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers (Box 157, Folder 5)
      - The Veteran, 1853-1904 (Box 157, Folder 18)
      - The Walls of Sand: A True Fairy Story, 1885 (Box 157, Folder 12)
      - Matter of Petition For Awarding Medal of Honor to Allen From 155th Regiment of Pennsylvania, 1862 (Box 157, Folder 13)
      - Memorial Day Address Given At Homewood Cemetary, 1901 (Box 157, Folder 14)
      - Fall In! Comrades, Written For The 155th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers, 1894 (Box 157, Folder 15)
      - Uniform Regalia, 1867 (Box 160, Folder 2)
      - Photographs of the 155th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers of the Civil War, 1908 (Box 158a, Folder 4)
    - Personal
      - Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings of Poems and Handwritten Poems, 1848-1849 (Box 159, Folder 3)
      - Journal Accounting Daily Life in Pittsburgh, 1849-1850 (Box 158a, Folder 5)
      - Small Notebook of Poetry, 1850-1914 (Box 159, Folder 4)
      - Journal Accounting Daily Life in Pittsburgh, 1851 (Box 158, Folder 6)
      - Journal Accounting Daily Life in Pittsburgh, a Christmas present from William, 1852 (Box 158, Folder 8)
      - Scrapbook Album Including Photos and Miscellaneous Allen Family Items, 1855 (Box 159, Folder 5)
      - Framed Portrait Upon Return From Washington Territory, 1855 (Box 158a, Folder 1)
      - Photographs and Portraits, Circa 1880s (Box 158a, Folder 2)
      - Photographs of Allen and Wife, Circa 1880s (Box 158a, Folder 3)
      - Mountain Department Map of Virginia, 1859 (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Pamphlets, 1863-1900 (Box 157, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1877-1914 (Box 157, Folder 6-11)
      - Framed Letter From Theodore Roosevelt, 1898 (Box 158, Folder 7)
        Framed letter addressed to Edward Jay Allen from then Assistant Secretary of the Navy Theodore Roosevelt, dated April 24, 1898.
      - Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings of Poetry by Edward, William and Other Authors and Articles Written by Edward About Numerous Travels, Published in the Pittsburgh Dispatch, 1853-1889 (Box 158, Folder 9)
      - Will and Last Testament, 1914; 1919 (Box 156, Folder 6)
      - Obituaries and Tributes, 1915-1918 (Box 157, Folder 19)
      - Portrait of John L. Burns (Box 159, Folder 6)
      - Newspaper Clippings Saved by Edward Jay Allen About the Civil War, Northwest History, and Family (Box 160, Folder 3)
      - Personal Ephemera (Box 157, Folder 16)
      - Portrait of Ulysses S. Grant (Box 159, Folder 7)
      - Woodcut Portrait Engraving (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - Immediate Family Correspondence, 1926-1954; 2.
    Correspondence between Hervey Allen and his wife and children.
    - Ann Andrews Allen, 1926-1930 (Box 161, Folder 1-12)
    - Ann Andrews Allen, 1931-1939 (Box 162, Folder 1-12)
    - Ann Andrews Allen, 1940-1949 (Box 163, Folder 1-13)
    - Marcia Allen (daughter), 1931-1954 (Box 163, Folder 14-16)
    - Mary Ann Allen (daughter), 1935-1953 (Box 164, Folder 1-3)
    - Richard Francis Allen (son), 1942-1949 (Box 164, Folder 4-12)
  - Extended Family Correspondence, 1838-1950; 3.
    Correspondence between Hervey Allen and his extended family. Some correspondence includes familial matters with non-relatives.
    - Andrews, Charles (father-in-law), 1927-1942 (Box 165, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Mrs. Charles (mother-in-law), 1927-1949 (Box 165, Folder 2-4)
    - Andrews, Charles (brother-in-law), 1928-1949 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Andrews, Paul Shipman, 1934-1949 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - Gill, Mrs. Ida B. (cousin), 1923-1949 (Box 165, Folder 7)
    - Harrowing, Mamie (cousin), 1933-1939 (Box 165, Folder 8)
    - Moore, Marie (cousin), 1921-1949 (Box 165, Folder 9)
    - Myers, Mrs. Helen M. (maternal grandmother) (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Myers, Joseph S. (cousin), 1934-1949 (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Percy (family maid), 1944 (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Elizabeth Robinson Allen (Mrs. Edward Jay Allen, grandmother), 1838-1914 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - William H. Allen (father), 1870-1926 (Box 166, Folder 2-8)
    - Helen Myers Allen (mother), 1886-1918 (Box 166, Folder 9-10)
    - Ethel Allen (2nd wife of father), 1925-1926 (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Edna Allen Rickmers (aunt), 1918-1929 (Box 166, Folder 12-15)
    - Edna Allen Rickmers (aunt), 1931-1949 (Box 167, Folder 1-5)
    - Edward Halkett Allen, Jr. (uncle), 1924-1926 (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Harold Allen (uncle), 1898-1929 (Box 167, Folder 7-15)
    - Harold Allen (uncle), 1926-1939 (Box 168, Folder 1-8)
    - May L. Allen (aunt), 1916-1923 (Box 168, Folder 9-12)
    - May L. Allen (aunt), 1924-1938 (Box 169, Folder 1-11)
    - May L. Allen (aunt), 1939-1945 (Box 170, Folder 1-3)
    - Edward Allen (brother), 1920-1941 (Box 170, Folder 4-8)
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), undated (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), July 4, 1918-March 23, 1928 (Box 170, Folder 10)
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), July 4, 1918-April 5, 1924
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), June 17, 1924-March 23, 1928
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), November 4, 1928-August 3, 1933 (Box 170, Folder 11)
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), November 4, 1928-December 1, 1930
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), January 15,1931-August 3, 1933
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), November 11, 1933-October 27, 1936 (Box 170, Folder 12)
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), November 11, 1933-June 8, 1934
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), August 9, 1934-October 27, 1936
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), January 4, 1938-December 23, 1939 (Box 170, Folder 13)
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), January 10,1940-August 23, 1944 (Box 170, Folder 14)
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), January 10,1940-July 2, 1943
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), July 28, 1943-August 23, 1944
    - Elizabeth Allen (sister), August 26, 1944-March 11, 1949 (Box 170, Folder 15)
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), August 26, 1944-February 27, 1946
      - Elizabeth Allen (sister), May 4, 1946-March 11, 1949
    - Helen Allen (sister), 1921-1949 (Box 171, Folder 1-4)
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), April 28, 1918-August 6, 1921 (Box 171, Folder 5)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), April 28, 1918-December 6, 1920
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), February 21, 1921-August 6, 1921
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), October 30, 1921-March 29, 1926 (Box 171, Folder 6)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), October 30,1921-December 22, 1923
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 26, 1924-March 29, 1926
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), November 30, 1926-August 14, 1929 (Box 171, Folder 7)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), November 30, 1926-April 30,1928
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), June 24, 1928-August 14, 1929
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 26, 1931-June 13, 1934 (Box 171, Folder 8)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 26, 1931-July 20, 1934
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 30, 1933-June 13, 1934
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), July 30, 1934-December 15, 1936 (Box 171, Folder 9)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), July 30, 1934-September 18, 1935
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), October 1, 1935-December 15, 1936
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), February 1, 1937-December 31, 1937 (Box 171, Folder 10)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), February 1, 1937-July 13, 1937
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), July 22, 1937-December 31, 1937
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 19, 1938-March 9, 1939 (Box 172, Folder 1)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 19, 1938-March 29, 1938
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), April 18, 1938-March 9, 1939
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), March 9, 1939-March 6, 1940 (Box 172, Folder 2)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), March 9, 1939-June 27, 1939
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), July 5, 1939-March 6, 1940
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), April 18, 1940-October 3, 1941 (Box 172, Folder 3)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), April 18, 1940-October 3, 1940
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 13,1941-October 3, 1941
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 28, 1942-July 20, 1943 (Box 172, Folder 4)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 28, 1942-June 15, 1942
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 15, 1942-July 20, 1943
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 3, 1943-May 4, 1945 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), August 3, 1943-May 15, 1944
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), July 7, 1944-May 4, 1945
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), May 9, 1945-September 19, 1946 (Box 172, Folder 6)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), May 9, 1945-September 2, 1945
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), September 27, 1945-September 19,1946
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), 1947 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 28, 1948-January 22, 1949 (Box 172, Folder 8)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 28, 1948-May 24, 1948
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), June 8, 1948-January 22, 1949
    - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 22, 1949-March 20, 1950 (Box 172, Folder 9)
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), January 22, 1949-February 23, 1949
      - Winthrop Allen (brother), March 17, 1949-March 20,1950
    - Edward H. Allen (cousin), 1926-1949 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - Edward J. Allen III (nephew), 1944 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - Sylvia Allen (niece), 1944-1947 (Box 172, Folder 12)
    - General Family Correspondence, 1901-1949 (Box 172, Folder 13-14)
    - Family Matters, 1925-1934 (Box 172, Folder 15)
  - Genealogy, Financial, and Official Documents, 1831-1930; 4.